<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>image processing on sergem&#39;s personal public notebook</title>
    <link>https://serge-m.github.io/tags/image-processing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in image processing on sergem&#39;s personal public notebook</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://serge-m.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 21:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://serge-m.github.io/tags/image-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reducing image size for emails and apps</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/reducing-image-size-for-emails-and-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/reducing-image-size-for-emails-and-apps/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time&amp;hellip;
I just wanted to share a project that my friends built with a bit of my guidance:
imagesize.memohub.pro/
Basically it&amp;rsquo;s a small web app that takes a bunch of images and compresses them to a neccessary size. Processing happens in a browser. Your images and photos stay in your computer and they are never uploaded to any server. It can be handldy when you need to attach many photos to an email, or there is a limitation on file size in visa application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OCR in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/ocr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/ocr/</guid>
      <description>A working solution to recognize a couple of pages scanned text (or photos with text) in Ubuntu 20:
# install tesseract sudo apt install tesseract-ocr # find module with the language you need apt-cache search tesseract-ocr # Let&#39;s say we need german. Then we install sudo apt install tesseract-ocr-deu # Install GUI tool sudo apt install ocrfeeder The interface is relatively simple. It may require setting the default language in the settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital color representation</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/digital-color-representation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/digital-color-representation/</guid>
      <description>Representation of color is messed up. Here are some articles about terminology.
Merging Computing with Studio Video: Converting Between R&amp;rsquo;G&amp;rsquo;B&amp;rsquo; and 4:2:2 / pdf by Charles Poynton
Upon conversion from 8-bit R&amp;rsquo;G&amp;rsquo;B&amp;rsquo; to 8-bit Y&amp;rsquo;CBCR, three-quarters of the available colors are lost. Upon 4:2:2 subsampling, half the color detail is discarded.
YUV and luminance considered harmful / pdf by Charles Poynton
It was standardized for NTSC in 1953, and remains standard for all contemporary video systems, to form luma, denoted Y’, as a weighted sum of nonlinear (gamma-corrected) R’G’B’ components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image processing cheat sheet</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/image-processing-cheat-sheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 21:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/image-processing-cheat-sheet/</guid>
      <description>In ImageMagick:
convert save the result to a given (new) file mogrify is the same as convert but it performs processing inplace (the input files are overwritten) Strip metadata from jpg file:
mogrify -strip f.jpg Rotate according the metadata, then strip:
mogrify -auto-orient -strip f.jpg Find jpg and jpeg images, apply orientation from EXIF, remove metadata and resize to 1920 on the longest side preserving the aspect ratio and save to the same files:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On image search</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/on-image-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 12:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/on-image-search/</guid>
      <description>ParaDISE - Parallel Distributed Image Search Engine. Based on Hadoop, probably offline processing.
Image Similarity service (github) - scala based image similarity service, declared to be scalable. Image storage and image similarity logic is implemented within independent, stateless micro-services. Data is stored in postgres. Clustering is based on histograms. 1 contributor. No tests. abandoned.
ViSense SDK for python - SDK for closed source image search
List of Content-based image retrieval (CBIR) engines (wikipedia)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image processing in Python</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/image-processing-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 07:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/image-processing-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Image search using elastic search Comparison of Image Search Performance using different kinds of vectors
Plugin for elastic search
Personalizing image search with feature vectors and Lucene (video)
Operations on images in python How to set thresholds for Canny edge detector in openCV Zero-parameter, automatic Canny edge detection with Python and OpenCV
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 def auto_canny(image, sigma=0.33): # compute the median of the single channel pixel intensities v = np.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
