<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>management on sergem&#39;s personal public notebook</title>
    <link>https://serge-m.github.io/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in management on sergem&#39;s personal public notebook</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://serge-m.github.io/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 22:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://serge-m.github.io/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OKRs</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/okrs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 22:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/okrs/</guid>
      <description>We had a production system written by mathematicians, 50 different stakeholders with conflicting targets, five leadership changes during last year, a dozen of microservices, AWS costs of 10 thousands per week,
hole galaxy of legacy databases, cron jobs, Celery, greenlets, … Also, unstable API as a dependency, 10 Gb of text dumps as output, user input without validation, false alarms in monitoring, and two dozen unprotected public endpoints. Not that we needed all that for the work, but once you get locked into a serious agile development, the tendency is to push it as far as you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about management</title>
      <link>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/about-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://serge-m.github.io/posts/about-management/</guid>
      <description>Why your programmers just want to code @justzeros
Interesting list of managers&amp;rsquo; readmes: 12 “Manager READMEs” from Silicon Valley’s Top Tech Companies
 Michael Lopp. How to Rands &amp;ndash; feels like really similar personality as me   I am an introvert and that means that prolonged exposure to humans is exhausting for me. Weird, huh? Meetings with three of us are perfect, three to eight are ok, and more than eight you will find that I am strangely quiet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
